<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Little Beras</title>
    <link href="https://littleberas.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://littleberas.github.io" />
    <updated>2024-05-21T10:39:32+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Andrew Huber</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://littleberas.github.io</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Join Us</title>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Huber</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://littleberas.github.io/join-us.html"/>
        <id>https://littleberas.github.io/join-us.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-21T10:25:21+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    You need to be a member of our WhatsApp group to get notifications about available spaces. Sign-up below to join the WhatsApp group. You will also need to have the Google Docs app on your phone to add your name to our weekly sign-up sheet.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>You need to be a member of our WhatsApp group to get notifications about available spaces. Sign-up below to join the WhatsApp group.</p>
<p>You will also need to have the Google Docs app on your phone to add your name to our weekly sign-up sheet.</p>
<p>We check new registrations once a week. This means it may be several days before you are added to the WhatsApp group.</p>
<p>If you have any questions or would like to get in touch you can email us at <a href="mailto:hello@littleberas.com">hello@littleberas.com</a></p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Volunteers Guide</title>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Huber</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://littleberas.github.io/volunteers-guide.html"/>
        <id>https://littleberas.github.io/volunteers-guide.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-21T10:23:56+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Sessions: Thursdays and Saturdays, 10am to 12pm Please send a message as soon as possible in the volunteer WhatsApp group. This helps us to make other arrangements. Welcome people to the group and ask them to sign in. Make sure buggies are parked to the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="entry-content">
<p>Sessions: Thursdays and Saturdays, 10am to 12pm</p>
<h2>If you can’t make it</h2>
<p>Please send a message as soon as possible in the volunteer WhatsApp group. This helps us to make other arrangements.</p>
<h2>Opening up (9.40am)</h2>
<ol>
<li>Buy milk, biscuits (and tea and coffee if needed) on your way.<br>Reimburse the cost from the cash box. The person(s) opening up will need to bring the cash box with them. The Hall won’t allow us to store the cash box there.</li>
<li>Unlock the padlock entering the 4 digit code (ask in admin WhatsApp group) in the top line.<br>Remove the padlock and keep it with you or lock it on the main gate. This is to ensure that it is not taken or that you are not locked in by anyone while using the hall.<br>If locking the padlock back to the gate, make sure the word ‘Master’ is facing outwards. You need to have the correct 4 numbers code in the top line to close it. Once closed then move around the numbers.</li>
<li>Unlock the main door.</li>
<li>Switch on the lights.<br>The light box is to your right as you enter the hallway. Switch on:
<ul>
<li>the top row (these are for toilets)</li>
<li>the middle row (the word ‘Hall’ is written above this row)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Make sure access to all fire exits are clear. These are:
<ul>
<li>two in the main hall on either side of the front of the stage</li>
<li>the front door</li>
<li>the rear fire exit behind the stage</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Set up the sign-in table, place the following on a table close to the door:
<ul>
<li>Cash box – ask key-holder to open</li>
<li>The sign-in book – write today’s date on a new page</li>
<li>Disclaimer forms for new attendees</li>
<li>Hand sanitiser</li>
<li>Anti-bacterial wipes</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Close the baby gate – you roll it across the entrance to the hall.</li>
<li>Set up the tea and coffee area in kitchen. Place cups, spoons, milk, tea, coffee and biscuits on the kitchen counter for self-service. Brew coffee using the machine. Filters are in the cupboard.<br>Tea, coffee and biscuits are in the large lunchbox labelled ‘Little Beras’ to store items. This is stored in one of the kitchen cupboards.</li>
</ol>
<h2>During the session (10am-12pm)</h2>
<p>Welcome people to the group and ask them to sign in. Make sure buggies are parked to the left and are not blocking any fire exits.</p>
<p>Ask new attendees to sign disclaimer forms.</p>
<p>Make sure people can access tea and coffee.</p>
<p>Keep an eye out where possible for anything that might pose a risk to attendees. E.g. the baby gate remains closed.</p>
<p>Start moving toys and equipment back to the cupboard at around 11.45am.</p>
<h2>Closing up (11.45pm-12.10pm)</h2>
<ol>
<li>Store all toys, mats, sign-in desk materials and other equipment. Put the children’s tables and chairs in last. Lock the cupboard.</li>
<li>Tidy the hall and return all chairs to the sides of the hall. Keep all fire exits clear. These are:
<ul>
<li>two in the main hall on either side of the front of the stage</li>
<li>the front door</li>
<li>the rear fire exit behind the stage</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>A volunteer must bring the cashbox home with them.</li>
<li>Tidy the kitchen:<br>Wash and dry any remaining cups and place into the cupboard. You won’t have time to run the dishwasher and empty it.<br>Clean the counters.<br>Put Little Beras tea and coffee box back in the cupboard. Anything left out will be thrown away by the cleaner each Monday.<br>Make sure any crumbs, etc. are thrown in the bin.</li>
<li>Sweep the hall using brushes stored in the kitchen.</li>
<li>Roll back the baby gate (button on left) and close the internal door into the hall.</li>
<li>Empty any nappies in the toilet bin into the black bin outside.</li>
<li>Turn off all lights:<br>Kitchen switches inside the kitchen to your left.<br>Lights for the hall are through a panel to the right of the main entrance as you face the door. Make sure the top row and the middle row (labelled ‘Hall’) are turned off. All lights in the panel should be in the ‘off’ position.</li>
<li>Lock up the front door and the padlock of main gate. Make sure to change the sequence of numbers at the top after locking it. The word ‘Master’ should be facing outwards.</li>
</ol>
<h2>Other information</h2>
<p><strong>Heating and ventilation:</strong><br>The heating is controlled remotely. Do not touch the controls. It turns on one hour and a half before the playgroup.</p>
<p><strong>No smoking:</strong><br>Smoking is not allowed in any part of the Bera Hall.</p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Health &amp; Safety Policy</title>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Huber</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://littleberas.github.io/health-and-safety-policy.html"/>
        <id>https://littleberas.github.io/health-and-safety-policy.html</id>

        <updated>2024-05-21T10:23:36+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    This document is a statement of aims, principles and procedures for ensuring Health and Safety at Little Bera’s Parent &amp; Toddler Group. It provides a framework for the creation of a safe environment in which to work and play. Health and safety is primarily the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="entry-content">
<p>This document is a statement of aims, principles and procedures for ensuring Health and Safety at Little Bera’s Parent &amp; Toddler Group. It provides a framework for the creation of a safe environment in which to work and play. Health and safety is primarily the responsibility of the parent/carer.</p>
<h2>Aims</h2>
<p>To provide adequate control of health and safety risks from the groups activities To provide and maintain safe equipment To prevent accidents to adults and children To maintain a safe and healthy group environment</p>
<p>PARENTS ARE ENCOURAGED TO:<br>Ensuring their children attend in good health.<br>Accept responsibility for the conduct of their children at all times.<br>Ensure the group has an up-to-date contact address and phone numbers in the event of an emergency.<br>Parents/carers will be present throughout the session and remain responsible for the children they bring with them.<br>Ensure all children are accompanied to the toilet. Any arrangements to take children other than one’s own should be agreed with the parent/carer Parents can make their own private arrangements to take each other’s children to the toilets or keep an eye on the children while one parent is busy. Parents should be aware that it is their own responsibility to ensure that such arrangements are satisfactory<br>Groups should ensure that babies and crawlers are neither harmed nor over-restricted by play activities and equipment which are provided for older children<br>Children should be adequately supervised at all times. Some potentially hazardous activities, such as water play, should be provided only if parents or other responsible adults ensure constant supervision<br>Sleeping babies should not be left unattended outside the premises, or out of sight of the group.<br>A suitable space should be found where parents can watch sleeping children<br>Children should not have access to any outside play area unless accompanied by an adult<br>Children should still be adequately supervised while their parents are talking or participating in adult activities. Groups which provide additional adult activities must ensure the safety of the children<br>Groups should take extra care about safety for children with special or additional needs and learning difficulties.</p>
<p>Although parents remain responsible for their own children, every adult within the group should be safety conscious. Everyone should be encouraged to prevent accidents and remove any hazards.</p>
<h2>Fire Safety</h2>
<p>Everyone must sign the attendance register at the beginning of the session (including any visitors). This becomes the role call in the event of an evacuation and is essential. If you leave early and even if you intend to return during that session, please put a tick by your name in the book so that it is clear you have left the premises.</p>
<h2>First Aid Policy</h2>
<p>Any child who is hurt during the session should be reunited as soon as possible with his/her parent. If first aid is necessary the parent should be consulted about any treatment<br>All accidents and any treatment administered are recorded in an accident book.</p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Group Guidelines</title>
        <author>
            <name>Andrew Huber</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://littleberas.github.io/guidelines.html"/>
        <id>https://littleberas.github.io/guidelines.html</id>

        <updated>2024-04-24T23:38:46+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Attendance For safety reasons we operate a limit on the number of people in attendance. Each week a link to a sign-up sheet will be shared in the WhatsApp group. There will be a set number of places available and a waiting list for cancelations.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <div class="entry-content">
<h2>Attendance</h2>
<p>For safety reasons we operate a limit on the number of people in attendance.</p>
<p>Each week a link to a sign-up sheet will be shared in the WhatsApp group. There will be a set number of places available and a waiting list for cancelations.</p>
<p>The first people to sign up using the link will get a place at that week’s session.</p>
<h2>Supervise your child at all times</h2>
<p>Parents/guardians and carers must look after their own children at all times. This is not a childcare or drop-off service.</p>
<p>Safety is the responsibility of all the adults attending the session.</p>
<h2>Entry fee</h2>
<p>Attendance is €2 per family. This covers tea/coffee and biscuits and running costs.</p>
<h2>Arrival time</h2>
<p>You don’t need to arrive at 10am, come along whenever suits you.</p>
<h2>Baby gate</h2>
<p>Make sure you close the baby gate when entering and leaving the hall.</p>
<h2>Helping out</h2>
<p>The group is run by volunteer parents. All parents and carers are asked to help in setting up and tidying up. Particularly putting toys away and washing up cups, etc.</p>
<h2>COVID-19 measures</h2>
<p>Please follow any COVID-19 measures we have in place. These may change over time.</p>
<p>Do not attend if you or your child has any symptoms of COVID-19.</p>
<h2>Fire safety</h2>
<p>Please do not park buggies near the entrance door as they can create an obstruction.</p>
<p>Make sure there are no chairs or other obstacles stacked beside the fire exits. These are:</p>
<ul>
<li>two in the main hall on either side of the front of the stage</li>
<li>the front door </li>
<li>the rear fire exit behind the stage</li>
</ul>
<p>Do not enter the stage area unless it’s an emergency.</p>
<h2>Toilets and nappies</h2>
<p>Children must be accompanied to the toilet by the parent/guardians or the adult nominated by the parent/guardians.</p>
<p>There is a nappy changing table in the ladies toilet. Please place wet and dirty nappies in the bin. There is one near the sink in the toilets and another in the kitchen.</p>
<h2>Kitchen area and hot drinks</h2>
<p>Children are not allowed in the kitchen area. We ask that all adults are extremely careful with hot drinks and do not bring them into the play area.</p>
<p>Please wash and dry your cup after use. Place it in the cupboard.</p>
<h2>Unsubscribe</h2>
<p>If you no longer wish to receive communications from Little Beras playgroup, please email <a href="mailto:hello@littleberas.com">hello@littleberas.com</a> with the subject line ‘Unsubscribe’.</p>
<p>Leave the WhatsApp group.</p>
<p>For more information you can contact us at <a href="mailto:hello@littleberas.com">hello@littleberas.com</a></p>
</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
